Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Char and Sayla's encounter...
...merely confirmed
how far apart their beliefs were.
The Zanzibar destroyed
Wakkein's Magellan as it fled from Texas.
And the White Base returned to Solomon.
The Newtype: Challia Bull
Until yesterday, Solomon had played
an important role...
...in the space strategy
of the Principality of Zeon.
But now it is serving as a base
for the Earth Federation Forces.
As a result, the Federation has gained
a vital foothold for its invasion of Zeon.
Soon reinforcements would arrive...
...and the Federation Forces would launch
a full-scale operation.
It seemed to be only a matter of time...
But then, a bizarre incident
occurred at Solomon.
I can hear it again! It says la, la.
Its course is E-6.
If you're there, you should see the enemy!
Eh? We're not done fixing
the electrical systems!
There's no way we could see it!
Hey! What happened? 38th Area! 38th Area!
General!
This is amazing...
Lalah is causing
all those bursts of light...
Even I find it hard to believe.
The Newtype Lalah
and the mobile armor Elmeth...
They're beyond all expectations.
What was that? Something exploded.
Marker! Where's the
enemy?!
I can't see it.
The Minovsky particle density is terrible...
What is it?
I feel like something's calling us.
Put all crew members
on anti-air surveillance!
Yes, sir!
Mirai. What's the matter?
Huh?
Are you feeling all right?
No, it's not that.
It's just... There's something
very strange around Solomon.
Strange?
Well, I do feel
a threatening presence...
Mr. Bright!
What is it?
The White Base is ordered to
await port entry at level 1 battle stations.
Roger!
Deck 1 and Deck 2!
Gundam, Guncannon, G-Fighter, take off!
All hands to level 1 battle stations!
They're working us to death here!
Hey, Kikka!
Yeah?
Could you guys bring me my normal suit?
Mr. Sunmalo would get mad.
Don't worry. I'm all better now.
Sayla. I believe in you, but...
Don't bring personal feelings into the battle.
Mr. Bright...
My actions thus far
have been sincere.
I was just confirming, as your commander.
I trust you.
Thank you.
This Is G-Fighter!
I'm ready for takeoff!
Is something the matter, Bright?
Mm.
I feel like Sayla is trying
to shoulder her troubles alone.
So it seems.
Here I go!
Guncannon taking off!
I guess it can't be helped.
I am a woman from Zeon.
Char's sister.
It's natural for him
not to trust me anymore.
Not again!
Something's calling me!
There's something...
I feel like it's... calling out for me.
What is it?
I can almost... see something.
Tired, Lalah?
Yes, Captain. But I'm fine.
I can keep going.
No. That'll be enough for today.
You've accomplished plenty already.
You should rest awhile.
Yes, Captain.
I can't hear it anymore.
What was I hearing anyway?
I'm sure... something was calling me.
A few hours before this incident...
...Gihren Zabi, Supreme Commander
of the Principality of Zeon's forces...
...was meeting with Lieutenant Challia Bull,
who had just returned from Jupiter.
Now that your fleet has returned...
...we need have no fear of a helium shortage.
I don't intend to allow this war
to continue for years to come.
You'd mentioned something about ending
the war in one month, Supreme Commander.
Don't say that, Challia Bull.
Please be seated.
Let's get to the main topic.
Right. Thank you very much.
Regarding the Newtypes you mentioned...
...I just have slightly sharper intuition
than a normal person.
I know more about you
than you do yourself.
Pardon?
I've gathered data showing your ability
as leader of the energy fleet to Jupiter.
The Flanagan Institute reviewed it.
The results are on the desk.
"Form of Newtype Development
in the Case of Challia Bull..."
You're saying I have those abilities?
That's right. You have abilities
you haven't even noticed.
Of course, there's much about Newtypes
we don't yet understand.
But I'd like to put those abilities to use.
Too many people have died in this war.
I'm to serve under Lady Kycilia?!
Ah. You knew it before I even said it.
Well done.
Kycilia has been preparing...
...a new mobile armor that will utilize
your fighting readiness.
As you wish, sir.
Good. The carrier Dolos is ready for you.
Sir!
Do you understand why
I'm sending you to serve under Kycilia?
Sir...
I can't tell what your
underlying intentions are, sir.
However, I will make every effort
to understand.
That will be fine, Challia Bull.
Attempting to read the minds of others
will only lead to one's own downfall...
But I ask that you reflect on why
I'm sending you to serve under Kycilia.
So the man named Challia Bull
is on this ship?
Yes, ma'am! We'll have him operate
the Braw Bro with Lieutenant Simus.
Good.
If this Lt. Challia Bull's abilities
are greater than those of Lalah...
...we should consider
giving him the Elmeth.
Make sure Captain Char understands that.
Yes, ma'am. I'll inform him.
A man who has returned from Jupiter?
As a Newtype, he might be
more promising than Lalah.
This console panel is surprisingly simple.
Lt. Simus, I'm ready when you are.
Let's launch!
Roger that, Lt. Challia Bull.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Have you found out
what's making Lalah so tired?
The voltage used to register her brainwaves
has a tendency to flow back...
...which affects Lalah.
Can you fix it?
We won't be able to control the Elmeth's bits
from long range like we did today, but...
We'll have to do it.
It may even work to our advantage.
It's harder for her to confirm the enemy
from a long distance.
I'm relieved to hear you say that.
Even if the psycommu does
enhance a person's intuition...
Lalah? Are you okay?
I'm fine...
I'll be ready for combat again in no time.
Lalah. If you get carried away in battle,
it could cost you your life.
I hear the Braw Bro will be here shortly.
Yes. Come on. We'll go to the bridge.
Yes, sir.
I'm a bit concerned about this Challia Bull.
Why's that?
I'm not certain whether he'll consider
what's best for you, Captain.
You don't need to worry
about things like that, Lalah.
Lt. Junior Grade Simus Bakharov
and Lt. Challia Bull...
...reporting for duty.
Welcome aboard. I'm Char.
This is Ensign Lalah Sune,
the Elmeth's pilot.
So this is Lalah,
the Flanagan Institute's star pupil?
Something wrong?
No. I was just wondering
about her lack of uniform.
I've been asking the supply corps for one.
We can't have her walking around the ship
like this. It's a problem.
Lieutenant Challia Bull...?
I see.
Captain. This young woman...
or rather, Ensign Lalah...
I can sense something from her.
It's like a kind of power...
And? What do you sense
from me, Lieutenant?
Oh! I do like people like yourself, Captain.
If you could try to be more broadminded...
...I believe it would be of
great benefit to Zeon.
I'll take that as a piece of good advice.
I feel as if I've made a new friend.
Welcome to the team, Lieutenant.
Thanks. If we are in fact Newtypes...
...I'm concerned about attaining peace
for all Newtypes.
Can I take that to mean
attaining peace for all humanity?
Of course!
Lalah. Do you understand
what the Lieutenant is saying?
Yes, sir.
It seems Ensign Lalah has great powers.
However, Lt. Challia Bull...
The problem is...
...the pilot of the Gundam mobile suit
appears to be a Newtype as well.
In other words, the Federation has already
deployed Newtypes in actual combat.
That's certainly possible.
Hayato! Are you allowed out of bed?
Sorry to worry you.
What's going on?
It's just that the Gundam's control system
has a tendency to overheat. That's why...
Why did you dispatch the Lieutenant alone?
He's too conscientious.
He insisted on testing the Braw Bro
and I couldn't dissuade him.
Oh, is that right?
You disapprove?
Until the Elmeth is adjusted
to suit you perfectly...
...I won't allow you to sortie.
Come in.
Sorry to call you here.
It's fine.
What is it, at a time like this?
I wanted to clear up your misunderstandings.
My misunderstandings?
You're angry with me, aren't you?
I'm close to Char, and I hid that from you.
Well, perhaps...
Char is my older brother.
Your brother?
Your older brother?
But then, how did you end up here?
The situation is... complicated.
So? Are you going to leave the ship?
No...
I don't think I can at this point.
The White Base means too much to me...
...And when I think of my brother
believing that he can do the impossible...
...I'd give my life to stop him!
Sayla!
My brother is a disgrace!
He's warped my father's true ideals
and thinks he can achieve them himself!
He's not my brother Casval anymore!
Is that his real name? Casval?
Yes... My brother... Casval...
And?
I'm sorry about this, Bright.
Here.
These are the gold bars
my brother gave me.
Please share them
among the White Base crew.
Is that what you really want?
I'd feel better that way...
I realize how self-centered that must sound.
You've chosen a difficult road.
I think I'm aware of it.
I understand.
I'll just treat you the same as I always have.
Thank you, Mr. Bright.
You know...
I can't help but admire your strength.
I really doubt this is going to be as easy
as you think it will be.
Still... I'll be counting on you, Sayla.
I know.
Possible enemy patrol ship detected!
Solomon requests that
we launch interceptors!
Are they going to make us do everything?!
It proves that they trust us, Bright.
Only as a decoy?
Right! Order all units to take off!
Gundam! Guncannon! G-Fighter!
Take off at once!
Hayato, are you okay?!
I feel great, Ms. Sayla!
I'll make up for the time I lost!
You'll just be observing for today,
until you get back on your feet!
Here it comes!
Looks like there are three machines...
No, it's...
I know it's not Lalah. It's somebody else!
Lt. Challia Bull, enemy detected.
I'll leave the fighting to you!
I'm not sure how much I can do,
but please record all the data.
Roger that!
Incoming, Lieutenant!
I see it! I'll give it my best try!
Th-This is incredible!
The enemy pilot can sense the direct line
between our position and Earth?!
What?!
It's different from the last one!
Below!
I knew it... The Gundam's reacting too slow!
What an amazing mobile suit and pilot.
That pilot has to be a genuine Newtype.
Otherwise, there's no way he could've
evaded the Braw Bro's all-range attack!
Th-There are two or three mobile armors?!
Pull back! This is unlike any
mobile armor we've seen before!
Pull back!
K-Kai! Where did it come from?!
M-Mr. Kai! Where's the enemy?!
Pull back! This enemy is different!
The Gundam's reacting too slow!
That pilot...!
He predicted I'd attack from the other side!
What's going on?!
The enemy should be just one mobile armor!
It's overheating!
The enemy is...!
What's wrong? Did he find us?!
Lt. Simus! Retreat!
What?!
I-I got him...
But I've pushed the Gundam
way past its breaking point.
The Gundam's control system
can't keep up with my speed!
If another enemy like that attacks,
we'll be toast.
Even Challia Bull was defeated...
If I launch in the Elmeth right now,
I can destroy the Gundam.
Don't underestimate him, Lalah.
The Federation's already deploying
Newtypes in battle, which means...
...the Gundam pilot may not be the only one.
You think so?
You must try to avoid risks in battle...
At least, the Gundam from Solomon
is too dangerous.
Besides...
We should think of Challia Bull.
He was an unfortunate man,
who knew that he was unable...
...to play right between
Lord Gihren and Lady Kycilia.
Letting him die honorably was
the best we could do for him.
Captain! You foresaw all this?
Lalah.
Newtypes are not omnipotent.
Perhaps they're just pathetic human
mutations spawned by war.
No...! That can't be true...!
Meanwhile, the White Base crew
was facing a grave situation.
Their fears about the Gundam's
control system had become reality...
In other words...
...the Gundam's system
could no longer keep up...
...with Amuro's ever-developing reflexes.
After a makeshift system is installed...
...the Gundam departs
to follow the Revil fleet.
Ahead of this fleet...
...within Zeon's defense line...
...one brilliant mobile armor
dances gracefully.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Lalah's Dilemma.
Next Time
Lalah's Dilemma
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...